<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LLNL on Valen Yamamoto</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/tags/llnl/</link><description>Recent content in LLNL on Valen Yamamoto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 20:46:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/tags/llnl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Machine Learning Internship @ LLNL</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/11/machine-learning-internship-@-llnl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 20:46:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/11/machine-learning-internship-@-llnl/</guid><description>My second summer internship at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) focused on comparing machine learning inference performance on novel AI hardware accelerators from Samba Nova and Cerebras to NVIDIA GPUs. I was working with a autoencoder model used to material interface reconstruction (MIR) for multi-material hydrodynamics codes. The neural network was proposed as an alternative to current solution PLIC: the neural network provided much smoother, continuous boundaries than PLIC, which could only give linear approximations.</description></item><item><title>HPCCEA Internship @ LLNL</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/08/hpccea-internship-@-llnl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 20:46:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/08/hpccea-internship-@-llnl/</guid><description>For my first internship, I worked at the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) as a part of the High Performance Computing Cluster Engineering Academy (HPCCEA) program. As a part of this program, I got to experience how the computing division of one the world&amp;rsquo;s pioneering supercomputing centers was run. I worked on installing computing nodes, writing bash scripts and eventually using Ansible to automate the proces of bring up a new node.</description></item></channel></rss>