<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>IEEE on Valen Yamamoto</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/tags/ieee/</link><description>Recent content in IEEE on Valen Yamamoto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 20:46:17 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/tags/ieee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Python Scripts for Parsing SPICE Output: A Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/04/python-scripts-for-parsing-spice-output-a-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 20:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/04/python-scripts-for-parsing-spice-output-a-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
Python is particularly useful for writing quick scripts. I find myself reaching for Python whenever I need to parse output into more readable/processable forms like csv files or pandas DataFrames. Engineering students at UCI don&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time learning Python, so I thought this would be a particularly useful exercise.
This workshop goes through a program to parse PSPICE output and allows the user to either output a csv version of the output or to pick out particular components with voltages or currents above a specified threshold.</description></item><item><title>MPI Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/11/mpi-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 20:46:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/11/mpi-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
After my internship at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, I decided to write on workshop on MPI for parallel programming. As large servers become more ubiquitous in most computer science workplaces, being able to write and execute multi-processor programs becomes more useful and feasible.
This workshop covers the following concepts:
blocking/non-blocking sends/receives openMPI for C mpi4py for Python buffers Collective Communication Routinues This workshop also has some Google Colab notebooks for participants to follow along with:</description></item></channel></rss>