<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NVIDIA on Valen Yamamoto</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/tags/nvidia/</link><description>Recent content in NVIDIA on Valen Yamamoto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/tags/nvidia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/about-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/about-me/</guid><description>Hello There! Welcome to my porfolio. Some things to check out while you are here&amp;hellip;
Checkout my CV here
Click through some other posts:
Cool Internships:
M2020 Rover @ JPL - Motion Planning for the M2020 and MSL mars rover arms! Hardware Accelerators @ LLNL - Optimizing the performance of an autoencoder for material interface reconstruction Parallel Algorithms @ LLNL - Optimizing matrix multipliation algorithm in distributed environments with architecture-specific instructions Select Workshops:</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/projects/</guid><description>Projects:
Deep Learning Framework FPGA RC Car</description></item><item><title>Computer Vision with the Jetson Nano Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/05/computer-vision-with-the-jetson-nano-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 20:45:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/05/computer-vision-with-the-jetson-nano-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
Since we still had those 15 Jetson Nanos (thanks NVIDIA!), we should probably do something more with them. And what better to do with them than computer vision.
This workshop covers the following concepts:
Convolution-based image processing kernels Gaussian, Low-pass blurs Sobel operators/ high pass filters Edge detection with Canny Edge Detector VPI Viewing CSI Cameras from the Jetson PyTorch for utilizing the GPU Flask website for streaming video</description></item><item><title>Intro to the Nvidia Jetson Nano</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/02/intro-to-the-nvidia-jetson-nano/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:45:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/02/intro-to-the-nvidia-jetson-nano/</guid><description>NVIDIA graciously provided the IEEE@UCI with 15 Jetson Nano single board computers to use for educational purposes, so I held a workshop allowing people to run through the Hello AI World tutorial NVIDIA set up.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Internship @ LLNL</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/11/machine-learning-internship-@-llnl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 20:46:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/11/machine-learning-internship-@-llnl/</guid><description>My second summer internship at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) focused on comparing machine learning inference performance on novel AI hardware accelerators from Samba Nova and Cerebras to NVIDIA GPUs. I was working with a autoencoder model used to material interface reconstruction (MIR) for multi-material hydrodynamics codes. The neural network was proposed as an alternative to current solution PLIC: the neural network provided much smoother, continuous boundaries than PLIC, which could only give linear approximations.</description></item></channel></rss>