<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Valen Yamamoto</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Valen Yamamoto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/about-me/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/about-me/</guid><description>Hello There! Welcome to my porfolio. Some things to check out while you are here&amp;hellip;
Checkout my CV here
Click through some other posts:
Cool Internships:
M2020 Rover @ JPL - Motion Planning for the M2020 and MSL mars rover arms! Hardware Accelerators @ LLNL - Optimizing the performance of an autoencoder for material interface reconstruction Parallel Algorithms @ LLNL - Optimizing matrix multipliation algorithm in distributed environments with architecture-specific instructions Select Workshops:</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/projects/</guid><description>Projects:
Deep Learning Framework FPGA RC Car</description></item><item><title>Workshops</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/workshops/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:14:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/11/workshops/</guid><description>As the project coordinator as the IEEE@UCI club, I&amp;rsquo;ve given many technical workshop over the last 3 years. Checkout the links below for more information on each workshop and to see the material.
List of Workshops:
Linux Workshop 2022 Computer Vision Workshop Jetson Nano Workshop Linux Dotfiles Workshop 2022 Linux Workshop 2021 PSPICE Python Scripting Workshop Linux Dotfiles Workshop 2021 MPI Workshop Neural Networks</description></item><item><title>Linux Workshop (Part 2)</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/10/linux-workshop-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 20:45:19 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/10/linux-workshop-part-2/</guid><description>Github Repository
Check out the first Linux workshop here
Rerunning last year&amp;rsquo;s workshop, I realized that I did not write down any information on what I said last year. So this year, I have made a powerpoint presentation to go with the workshop.
Other than the presentation, the workshop is mostly unchanged.</description></item><item><title>JPL M2020 Internship</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/08/jpl-m2020-internship/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 20:46:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/08/jpl-m2020-internship/</guid><description>I worked in Section 374K with Justin Huang implementing RRTConnect has a motion planning algorithm for the the 5 DOF arms on the Mars rovers. Usually in motion planning, paths are smoothed to make corners into curves for less jerky motion; however, for space robotics, planners try to send the least amount of data through space to the rovers so the minimal number of viapoints is preferred. So instead of smoothing the RRT-generated paths, I spent the majority of my time simplifying the paths to the smallest number of viapoints.</description></item><item><title>Computer Vision with the Jetson Nano Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/05/computer-vision-with-the-jetson-nano-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 20:45:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/05/computer-vision-with-the-jetson-nano-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
Since we still had those 15 Jetson Nanos (thanks NVIDIA!), we should probably do something more with them. And what better to do with them than computer vision.
This workshop covers the following concepts:
Convolution-based image processing kernels Gaussian, Low-pass blurs Sobel operators/ high pass filters Edge detection with Canny Edge Detector VPI Viewing CSI Cameras from the Jetson PyTorch for utilizing the GPU Flask website for streaming video</description></item><item><title>Linux Dotfiles Workshop (Part 2)</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/04/linux-dotfiles-workshop-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:45:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/04/linux-dotfiles-workshop-part-2/</guid><description>Github Repository
Check out the first dotfiles workshop here
For the second time around, I&amp;rsquo;ve added some more information on topics I feel would be useful for engineering students who have to sign into the servers for our assignments.
The additional information added to this workshop:
Aliasing .vim folder and ftplugins SSH keys and passwordless ssh sign in, .ssh folder The linux filesystem (inodes, hardlinks vs. softlinks)</description></item><item><title>Intro to the Nvidia Jetson Nano</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/02/intro-to-the-nvidia-jetson-nano/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:45:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2022/02/intro-to-the-nvidia-jetson-nano/</guid><description>NVIDIA graciously provided the IEEE@UCI with 15 Jetson Nano single board computers to use for educational purposes, so I held a workshop allowing people to run through the Hello AI World tutorial NVIDIA set up.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Internship @ LLNL</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/11/machine-learning-internship-llnl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 20:46:33 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/11/machine-learning-internship-llnl/</guid><description>My second summer internship at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) focused on comparing machine learning inference performance on novel AI hardware accelerators from Samba Nova and Cerebras to NVIDIA GPUs. I was working with a autoencoder model used to material interface reconstruction (MIR) for multi-material hydrodynamics codes. The neural network was proposed as an alternative to current solution PLIC: the neural network provided much smoother, continuous boundaries than PLIC, which could only give linear approximations.</description></item><item><title>Linux Command Line Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/10/linux-command-line-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 20:38:24 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/10/linux-command-line-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
All engineers will eventually have to use the Linux command line either on the job or in classes; however, the command line is barely taught in classes. While a rudimentary understanding of the command line is needed to get most tasks done, knowing some additional tips and tricks can make work much easier and faster. The goal of the workshop was to introduce the Linux command line interface as well as common commands that all engineers should know.</description></item><item><title>Linux Dotfiles Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/05/linux-dotfiles-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 20:45:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/05/linux-dotfiles-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
Everyone in engineering has to use a Linux terminal once in a while. Why not customize your experience? This workshop was conceived as a fast, easy workshop to run during midterms while also giving useful information on how to increase productivity in the shell environment.
This workshop covers the following topics:
hidden files in Linux .vimrc file for vim settings .bashrc for shell settings custom bash prompts aliases .</description></item><item><title>Python Scripts for Parsing SPICE Output: A Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/04/python-scripts-for-parsing-spice-output-a-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 20:46:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2021/04/python-scripts-for-parsing-spice-output-a-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
Python is particularly useful for writing quick scripts. I find myself reaching for Python whenever I need to parse output into more readable/processable forms like csv files or pandas DataFrames. Engineering students at UCI don&amp;rsquo;t spend a lot of time learning Python, so I thought this would be a particularly useful exercise.
This workshop goes through a program to parse PSPICE output and allows the user to either output a csv version of the output or to pick out particular components with voltages or currents above a specified threshold.</description></item><item><title>Deep Learning Framework in C++</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/12/deep-learning-framework-in-c-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 17:38:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/12/deep-learning-framework-in-c-/</guid><description>Github Repository
Ever since I started learning PyTorch, I have been fascinated by the automatic gradient feature. In order to further understand it, I decided I would try to write my own version. At the time, I was also taking a C++ class, so I decided to both learn about autograd and study for my finals. (As well as do the required project to initiate into IEEE-HKN)
This program dynamically constructs a computation graph as operations are done.</description></item><item><title>MPI Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/11/mpi-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 20:46:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/11/mpi-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
After my internship at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, I decided to write on workshop on MPI for parallel programming. As large servers become more ubiquitous in most computer science workplaces, being able to write and execute multi-processor programs becomes more useful and feasible.
This workshop covers the following concepts:
blocking/non-blocking sends/receives openMPI for C mpi4py for Python buffers Collective Communication Routinues This workshop also has some Google Colab notebooks for participants to follow along with:</description></item><item><title>Neural Networks with PyTorch Workshop</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/10/neural-networks-with-pytorch-workshop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 20:46:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/10/neural-networks-with-pytorch-workshop/</guid><description>Github Repository
For my first workshop for the IEEE@UCI, I wanted to talk about something I found interesting, so I decided to do a workshop on neural networks. Because of its recently growing popularity, most engineering students have heard of neural networks, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily understand how they work.
My goal with this workshop was to both introduce people to the math behind neural networks and to let people have hands-on practice composing and training a neural network.</description></item><item><title>HPCCEA Internship @ LLNL</title><link>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/08/hpccea-internship-llnl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 20:46:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://ValenYamamoto.github.io/2020/08/hpccea-internship-llnl/</guid><description>For my first internship, I worked at the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) as a part of the High Performance Computing Cluster Engineering Academy (HPCCEA) program. As a part of this program, I got to experience how the computing division of one the world&amp;rsquo;s pioneering supercomputing centers was run. I worked on installing computing nodes, writing bash scripts and eventually using Ansible to automate the proces of bring up a new node.</description></item></channel></rss>